

Utsav Baral

React.js | UI/UX Developer

Pharatpur, Nepal

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/utsavbaral7/

https://www.utsavbaral.com.np/

https://github.com/utsavbaral007

PROFILE

I'm a Frontend and UI/UX Developer with a little over two years of experience in developing web applications. I have a passion for creating websites that users love to interact with. I enjoy working with a variety of technologies and design principles to make sure that the users get a seamless experience. I am Currently pursuing Masters degree in Computer Science and Information Technology from Tribhuvan University.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

06/2021 - 10/2021 Lalitpur, Nepal

InfoDevelopers Pvt. Ltd. 🖸

UI/UX Engineer

- UI Development for Digital Wallet system ConnectIPS and CorporatePAY.
- UI and Web Application Development for Ministry of Federal Affairs and General Administration. (React.js)
- UI and Web Application Development for Government Integrated Office Management System. (React.js)
- UI and Web Application Development for Ministry of Health, Ministry of Land Reform and Management, Nepal Police Website and Dashboard, Subsidiary of Sanima Bank Limited and Digital Lending System (Rapi Money). (React.js and Vue.js)

10/2020 - 06/2021 Kathmandu, Nepal

Prismasofts

Software Developer

- Development of Real Estate Website using React is, Node is and Firebase.
- Development of Customer Data Management Web App using React.js, Node.js and Firebase.
- Development of Prismasoft's Website using React.js.
- React.js basics and responsive web design mentor for new interns.

06/2020 - 09/2020 Kathmandu, Nepal

Learngaroo Learning 🖸

Web Developer - Internship

- Build REST API using Flask.
- Basic usage of AWS services such as, S3 bucket and Transcribe.
- Company website landing page design using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

05/2019 - 05/2020 Lalitpur, Nepal

Incwell Venture Pvt. Ltd.

Bootcamp, Internship and Software Developer

- In-house project, Leave Management System(LMS) using React.js.
- Black Forest website using HTML, CSS and JS.

PROJECTS

Instagram Clone

MERN Stack

- Instagram Clone developed using React is as frontend library, Node is on top of Express is and Mongodb as database.
- Used JWT for authentication, Context API for state management.

COVID-19 Tracker

React.js, Chart.js

- COVID-19 Tracker web app developed using React.js.
- Chart.js is used for visualization of the data.
- Leaflet is used for displaying the stats on a map for different countries.

E-commerce app UI

React.js, Bootstrap, SASS

• E-commerce website UI developed using React.js, Bootstrap and SASS

EDUCATION

11/2021 – present Kathmandu, Nepal Masters in Computer Science and Information Technology

Tribhuvan University

11/2014 – 08/2018 Lalitpur, Nepal **Bachelors in Computer Science and Information Technology**

Himalaya College of Engineering

SKILLS

• HTML5 and CSS3

• JavaScript

• React.js

• Redux and Context API

• Git

• Bootstrap

• Ant Design